iec.ch 2018-05-20

# IEC - About the IEC > Privacy policy

Thank you for visiting the IEC (International Electrotechnical Commission) Website. The IEC is committed to protecting the privacy of its members, customers and other contacts. Any information you choose to provide on this Website will only be used to provide or improve the services we offer.

## General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

The IEC is currently working on adapting this policy to ensure compliance with GDPR regulation EU 2016/679.

## Revisions

The IEC reserves the right to change or modify this Privacy Policy at any time. If we revise our policy, we will post the changes on the site to ensure transparency in informing you about what information we collect, how we use it and under which circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

## Acceptance 

The IEC does not collect personally identifying data from this Website except when specifically and knowingly provided by you. By browsing this Website and communicating electronically with us and/or submitting your personal data to this Website, you acknowledge and agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and to the processing of personal data by the IEC as described below. 

One of the purposes of the IEC collecting personal information is to provide you with the best possible service. 

## Personal Information

We may collect information about you when you use this Website, or when you apply for or use other services offered by the IEC, in the following ways: 

  * As you browse through the IEC Website, we may automatically gather and store information about your visit via cookies. We may use session-specific cookies to collect data automatically about Website use when you visit this site, including e.g. your IP address, domain name, Internet service provider, protocol, browser type and operating system. This information is notably required when you use the IEC’s [Webstore](http://webstore.iec.ch/) to purchase IEC publications.  

  * When you use our [Webstore](http://webstore.iec.ch/) to purchase IEC publications, or subscribe to our online magazines (iec e-tech or [Just Published](http://webstore.iec.ch/justpublished)), or subscribe to MyNewDocs, or request specific information or products, we will use the personal data that you provide only for such purposes as are described at the point of collection and at the time of data input, such as to send you information or ordered products, to update your membership record or to respond to your questions and comments.  

  * The IEC will use such personally identifying data as (without restriction) full name, address, e-mail, phone and fax numbers only for business purposes within the IEC, which includes communication of the data to the IEC member National Committees. If you are a person who has been nominated to participate in IEC work, your National Committee has access to your record and can modify it in accordance with your legal rights. This data may also be made available to the officers of the committee, project team, working group or maintenance team to permit them to contact you.   

  * Membership lists of committees and subgroups are available publicly on the IEC Website. These lists include only the name and country of each participant. No means of contact information (notably e-mail, address and phone/ fax number) are given.

## Surveys 

From time to time, we may ask our site visitors to answer survey questions. Surveys generally deal with the site, our products or categories of products. They will not request any personal data. 

## Referrals 

Some areas of the IEC Website may provide you with the opportunity to e-mail a Web page to another person. For this feature to work, we may need to collect your e-mail address and/or the e-mail addresses of those to whom you send the page. The e-mail addresses collected in this context are not used for any purpose other than to send the Web page in question. 

## Links to Other Sites

The IEC Website contains links to other sites. Links to third-party Websites lie outside the scope of responsibility of the IEC. Access to and use of such Websites occurs entirely at the user’s own risk. The IEC expressly states that it has no influence whatsoever over the content of any linked site. Responsibility for information and services of linked sites rests entirely with the relevant third parties. No liability can be accepted in respect of the content of such Websites.

## Data Protection and Accessing, Deleting or Correcting of Data

Based on Article 13 of the Federal Constitution and the provisions of the Swiss data protection legislation, everyone has the right to the protection of privacy, as well as to protection from misuse of their personal details. The IEC complies with these provisions. Personal details are treated in the highest confidence and are neither passed on, shared nor sold to third parties (whether situated in a country providing standards of protection similar to those of Switzerland or not) except in the following case:

> **The IEC may disclose personal data to third parties (whether situated in a country providing standards of protection similar to those of Switzerland or not) if the IEC is required to do so by law or if such action is reasonably necessary to comply with legal process, to respond to any claims, or to protect the rights of the IEC, its customers and the public.** For the purposes of this clause, National Committees of the IEC, even when situated outside Switzerland, are not deemed to be third parties and you hereby consent to the transfer of personal data to such National Committees for the purpose of managing your participation in IEC work. 

You can consult, revise and correct the personal data that you have provided to the IEC Webstore via [http://webstore.iec.ch](http://webstore.iec.ch/). To revise or correct personal data relating to your participation in IEC work, you should contact your National Committee. If you wish to correct data relating to your position or function in an IEC committee (for example, National Committee official, TC/SC secretary, chairman, PT leader or WG/MT convenor), you should contact the IEC Central Office.

We will retain your personal information in accordance with applicable data protection laws for so long as it is needed in the light of the principle of proportionality. 

## Copyright or IP rights 

Downloading or copying of texts, illustrations, photos or any other data does not entail any transfer of rights on the content. Copyright and any other IP rights relating to texts, illustrations, photos or any other data available on [http://www.iec.ch](http://www.iec.ch/) are the exclusive property of the IEC or of any other expressly mentioned owners. Any reproduction requires the prior written consent of the copyright holder. 

## Governing Law and Jurisdiction 

This IEC Website Privacy Policy is governed by and construed **_in accordance with the laws of_** ** _Switzerland_**. You agree that any dispute arising out of your use of this Web site is **_subject to the exclusive_** ** _jurisdiction of the courts in_** ** _Geneva_** ** _,_** ** _Switzerland_**.
